《明日之后》
（南极，拉尔森B冰棚）
明白吗？
我相信已经掌握到
最好掌握到，钻坏了冰湟捱骂
You better. The boss wiII chew my head off
if these cores get messed up.
放心好了
Don't worry.
我们钻到廿六尺
We're at 26 feet.
你让泽逊去钻？
You let Jason operate the drill?
他应付得来
Yeah, he can handle it.
不关我事！
l didn't do anything.
伸只手过来！放开把钻！
Give me your hand!
Let go of the drill!
算了，阿积！来不及！
Forget it, Jack! lt's too late!
你跳不回来！
You're not gonna make it!
阿积！
Jack!
阿积！伸只手上来！
Jack! Give me your hand!
我捉住你了！
l've got you!
你搞什么？
What were you thinking?
-发生什么事？
-整个冰棚裂开了！
-What's happening?
-The whole damn shelf is breaking off!
就是发生了这种事！
That's what's happening!
我们发现了一万年前出现
过灾难性气候变化的证据
We found evidence of a cataclysmic climate
shift, which occurred 1 0,000 years ago.
（新德里，联合国全球暖化会议）
从冰渲刑烊晃率移体的浓度K
The concentration of these natural
greenhouse gases in the ice cores...
可知暖化曾经加速，把地球K
...indicates that runaway warming
pushed Earth into an ice age...
推入长达二百年的冰河时期
...which lasted two centuries.
我不明白
l'm confused.
我以为你在说全球暖化
不是冰河时期
l thought you were talking about
global warming, not an ice age.
说来矛盾，不过
全球暖化可以触发气温下降
Yes, it is a paradox, but global warming can
trigger a cooling trend. Let me explain.
北半球气温取决于北大西洋海流
The Northern Hemisphere owes its climate
to the North Atlantic Current.
海洋把太阳热力从赤道带上北方
Heat from the sun arrives at the equator
and is carried north by the ocean.
全球暖化令地极冰盖溶解
减弱了暖流
But global warming is melting the polar
ice caps and disrupting this flow.
最终会令暖流消失
当这情况发生时K
Eventually it will shut down.
And when that occurs...
温暖气候也随之而消失
...there goes our warm climate.
教授，这种情况
你认为几时会出现？
Excuse me. When do you think this
could happen, professor? When?
我不知道，可能一百年后
可能一千年后，但我知道的是K
l don't know. Maybe in 1 00 years,
maybe in 1 000. But what l do know is...
假如我们不尽快补救
我们的子孙会付出代价
...that if we do not act soon, our children
and grandchildren will have to pay the price.
防止全球暖化，代价很高
And who's going to pay the price
of the Kyoto Accord?
全球要付出数以千亿美元
lt would cost the world's economy
hundreds of billions of dollars.
副总统先生，置诸不理的代价更高
With all due respect, Mr. vice President, the
cost of doing nothing could be even higher.
地球气候是脆弱的
Our climate is fragile.
我们过度消耗石油，污染环境K
At the rate we're burning fossil fuels
and polluting the environment...
冰盖很快会消失
...the ice caps will soon disappear.
贺教授K
Professor Hall...
我们的经济同环境一样脆弱
...our economy is every bit as fragile
as the environment.
你未语出惊人之前
请先记住这点
Perhaps you should keep that in mind
before making sensationalist claims.
上次断裂的冰棚K
Well, the last chunk of ice
that broke off...
有罗德岛那样大
...was about the size of Rhode lsland.
有些人认为那是很惊人的
Some people might call that
pretty sensational.
防止全球暖化！防止全球暖化！
Stop global warming!
正举行全球暖化会议的新德里K
l'm at the Global Warming Conference
in New Delhi...
说来难以置信，竟然下起雪来
...where, if you can believe it,
it's snowing.
有史以来最冻的气候
引起一片混乱K
The coldest weather on record
has thrown the city into chaos...
很多露宿者冻死
...with numbers of homeless people
freezing to death.
的士！的士！
Taxi!
教授，你的证供非常精采
l enjoyed your testimony, professor.
lt was very spirited.
多谢，这就是这次活动的目的
做一场好骚
Oh, thank you. That's what we're
here for, right? Put on a good show?
我想同你讨论你的
气候突变理论
Quite. l was wondering if l could talk to you
about your theory on abrupt climate shift.
我叫擦臣，泰利擦臣
The name's Rapson. Terry Rapson.
-擦臣教授？在赫兰中心工作的？
-就是我
-Professor Rapson? Of the Hedland Center?
-That's me.
我读过你关于海流的大作
l've read your work on ocean currents.
-一起喝杯茶好吗？
-当然，如果截到的士的话
-What do you say to a spot of tea?
-Absolutely. lf we can hail a cab.
这里
Over here.
欢迎继续收看
我们在格拉斯哥的直播，曼联K
Welcome back to Glasgow, Scotland,
where Manchester United...
领先主队流浪三比一
...leads 3- 1 over hometown Celtic.
（苏格兰，赫兰气象研究中心）
现在是下半场十八分钟，曼联K
We return 63 minutes into
the second half as Manchester United...
乘胜追击
现在把时间交给评论员K
...looks to put the game out of reach.
Let's get back to our commentator...
当奴麦法兰
...Donald MacFarland.
什么？好
What? Yeah.
-我只是闭目养神
-对
-l just closed my eyes for a sec, man.
-Yeah.
昨晚BB吵通宵
The baby kept us awake all night.
-仍然系
-好！
-And still.
-Yeah!
气象浮标4311探测到气温
下降了十三度
Dennis? NOMAD buoy 431 1 is showing
a temperature drop of 1 3 degrees.
-浮标4311在哪里？
-它在K
-Yeah? Where is 431 1 ?
-Well, it's....
-乔治海岸
-那处很大浪
-Georges Bank.
-lt's rough seas out there.
浮标一定是给浪抛坏了
Must have knocked it about.
交波啦！
Kick that bloody ball. Come on!
射！射！
Come on, kick it now. Kick it!
-射！
-曼联领先？
-Kick it!
-Are the lads winning?
教授，印度的旅程怎样？
Hello, professor. How was lndia?
你知道这些科学会议都是怎样的
Oh, you know what these
scientific gatherings are.
总是离不开醇酒美人
All dancing girls, wine and parties.
（东京，千代田区）
你回家未？
刚刚从公司出来
咙风娜兰妮来势がぁK
The fury of Hurricane Noelani
stunned weather experts yesterday...
在列岛上造成严重损毁
...slamming into the island chain with a
cataclysmic force never before witnessed.
天气专家大感意外
认为这是有史以来最强烈的咙风K
Meteorologists already believe this to be
the strongest hurricane ever recorded....
为什么不听电话？
Are you gonna get that?
相信会做成很多人死亡K
It will surely leave a wake of death....
-喂？
-我收到阿森的成绩表，微积分肥佬
-Hello?
-l just saw that Sam got an F in calculus.
我知道，我也收到成绩表的副本
I'm aware, Jack.
I get a copy of his report card too.
阿森一向是优异生，不会不合格
Sam is a straight-A student.
He doesn't fail classes.
我现在没有时间讨论
l don't have time to talk about this now.
或者你应该抽空
Well, maybe you ought to make time.
经常失踪几个月的不是我
Excuse me, l'm not the one who's away
for months and months at a time.
我实在不明白
I just don't understand.
我会让他亲自向你解释
你明早可以送他机吗？
I'll let him explain it. Can you take him
to the airport in the morning?
-阿森要搭飞机？
-他要去参加校际常识问答比赛
-Sam's getting on a plane?
-He joined the Scholastic Decathlon Team.
-比赛在纽约举行
-阿森参加比赛？
-They're competing in New York.
-Sam joined a team?
-相信是为了一个女仔
-是吗？
-Yeah, l think there's a girl involved.
-Oh.
可以八点半来接他吗？
Look, can you pick him up at 8:30?
我要收线，因为今晚要当值
l gotta go because l'm on call tonight.
不要迟到，我不希望他再搭的士
Don't be late. l don't want
him taking a taxi again.
好，我会去
All right. Okay. l'll be there.
Okay? l'll be there.
气候员工会议改在四楼B会议室举行
This morning's weather staff meeting
has been moved to level four, room B.
（国家海洋大气管理局）
积？
Jack?
我知道你向来直肠直肚K
l know you're good at rubbing people
the wrong way...
但为什么连副总统也得罪？
...but why would you aggravate
the vice president?
因为我那十七岁儿子比他更懂科学
Because my 1 7-year-old kid
knows more science than he does.
但不是你儿子控制我们的预算
Your 1 7-year-old kid
does not control our budget.
-即使他恨你也无关系
-我儿子并不恨我
-Who cares if he hates you.
-My son doesn't hate me.
假如副总统停止拨款K
lf Raymond Becker pulls our budget--
-弊！
-你做K积！
-Oh, shit!
-Wait-- Will you--? Jack.
我的天
Oh, my God.
-对不起我迟到了
-的士已经到了
-l'm sorry l'm late.
-Dad, the cab's already here.
不要紧，我会打发他
That's okay. l'll take care of it.
-你要怎K？
-给你
-What are--?
-Here you go.
我不是生气，只是失望
l'm not angry. l'm disappointed.
-想听听我的版本吗？
-怎可能有两个版本呢？
-Do you want to hear my side of it?
-How can there be two sides?
我考到满分，但史老师肥我K
l got every question right on the final.
Mr. Spengler failed me...
-因为我没有写下计算步骤
-为什么不写？
-...because l didn't write the solutions.
-Why not?
我用心算
l do them in my head.
-你有没有告诉他？
-我有，但他不信
-Did you tell him that?
-l did. He didn't believe me.
他说他也不能用心算计出来
所以我必定是作弊
He said if he can't do them in his head,
l'm cheating.
他不能因为不够你聪明而肥你
Ridiculous. How can he fail you
for being smarter than he is?
我也是那样说
That's what l said.
你那样说？
You did?
-他有什么反应？
-他肥了我，记得吗？
-How'd he take it?
-He flunked me, remember?
对
Oh, yeah.
对不起，我不应该妄下结论
Sam, l'm sorry.
l jumped to conclusions.
我会打电话找他谈谈
l'm gonna call this guy
and have a word with him.
我们会取回公道
We'll straighten this out.
喂，你不可以在这里停车
Hey, you can't park there.
-算了吧
-森！
-Don't worry about it.
-Sam?
森
Sam.
柏加，这是侯斯顿
Parker, this is Houston.
卡纳维拉尔角天气恶劣
We're seeing some bad weather
over Canaveral.
今个星期你们不能回地球
It doesn't look like you're coming back
this week.
你太太不会放过我
Your wife's gonna give me an earful.
收到
Roger that.
过来看看这风暴，好巨型
Hey, come take a look at this storm system.
lt's enormous.
你没事吧？
You all right?
他怕搭飞机
He's afraid of flying.
我没事
l'm fine.
（不准吸烟
扣上安全带）
根据统计数字
因气流而坠机的机会K
Statistically, the chance of a plane
going down because of turbulence...
低于十亿份之一？
抑或百万份之一？
...is less than, what, one in a billion?
Or is it a million?
-我记不起K
-收声，拜仁
-l can't remember if it's a--
-Shut up, Brian.
森K
Listen, Sam...
不要理会他，没事的
...don't pay attention to him, okay?
Everything's fine.
空姐依然狈饮品出来
They're still serving drinks.
各位，航机会有点震荡
Folks, it appears we're gonna have a bit
of a bumpy ride for the next few minutes.
请系上安全带
把前面小桌折K
Please fasten your seat belts
and put your tray tables...
和椅子放回原来的位置
直至震荡完结，多谢合作
...and seat backs in their upright positions
until we get through this. Thank you.
哗！
Whoa!
捉住它，小心！
Grab it. Watch out!
森？
Sam?
森
Sam.
我可以缩手吗？
Can l have my hand back?
想不到我要陪我妈去度假
l can't believe l'll be alone
with my mom.
耐心点，她一直期待着这个假期
Be patient with her.
She's been looking forward to this holiday.
我知道
l know.
我爱你
l love you.
我也爱你
l love you too.
喂
Hey.
拜拜
Hey, hello. Bye-bye.
导致天气极度反常的原因依然不明
但有些专家认为K
The cause of this extreme weather remains
a mystery, although some meteorologists...
是太阳黑子所致K
...believe sunspots are to blame.
Hundreds are missing....
奇怪，气象浮标量度到
海洋温度下降了十三度
This is very odd. There's a buoy registering
a 1 3-degree drop in ocean temperature.
对，那乔治海岸的浮标坏了好几日
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That buoy malfunctioned the other day.
我会找附近的船收回它
l'll see if there are ships near
Georges Bank to get it.
这浮标不是在乔治，是在格钞兰
This buoy isn't in Georges Bank.
lt's just off Greenland.
什么？
What?
-两个浮标同时失灵的机会有几大？
-不大可能
-What are the odds of two buoys failing?
-Remote.
是三个同时失灵
Make that three.
又是纽约的惯常情形
车龙有十条街长！
Just another typical day in New York City.
Traffic jam, 1 0 blocks long.
看吧，阿宝
这些人，他们的汽车排出大量废气K
Look here, Buddha. These people,
and their cars, and their exhaust...
污染大气层
...and they're polluting the atmosphere.
对不起，我们非常赶时间
Excuse me, sir. We're really late.
快到了
We're almost there.
-只差两条街
-我们行路去吧
-We're only two blocks away.
-Let's walk.
动物有什么不妥？
What's gotten into them?
不知道，今天特别烦躁
l have no idea.
They're all worked up today.
在1532年，西班牙征服者
法兰西斯高皮萨路K
ln 1 532, Spanish conquistador
Francisco Pizarro...
在秘鲁高原的卡也马卡镇击败
印加的皇帝
...defeated this lncan emperor at the
Peruvian highland town of Cajamarca.
那皇帝叫什么名？计时
What is his name? Time.
孟迪苏马
Montezuma.
不是，孟迪苏马是在墨西哥
不是在秘鲁
No, no, Montezuma was in Mexico,
not Peru.
叫安他什么
lt's, like, Anta-something.
-安他华尔帕？
-没错！
-Atahualpa?
-That's it!
够钟，请回答
Time's up. Correct answers, please.
活蒙学校五分，`合学校五分
That's five points for Woodmont
and five points for Pinehurst Academy.
下条题目
Next question.
路易十四哪一年在法国登基？
ln what year did Louis Quatorze
ascend to the throne of France?
这里太古老，古老到可以当时兴
This place is so retro, it might actually
be cool if it were on purpose.
看，一大班书虫
Yeah, look at all these nerds.
喂
Hey.
你好漂亮
You look beautiful.
多谢，这个地方很有气派
Thanks. This place is incredible.
真不敢相信这是他们的饭堂
Do you believe this is their cafeteria?
你们在比赛中有好表现
You played a great first round.
你们也是
So did you.
我的队友，森和拜仁
These are my teammates,
Sam and Brian.
-我叫罗拉
-我叫⒇D
-l'm Laura.
-Oh, l'm J.D.
-你的学校好宏伟
-想参观吗？
-Your school's amazing.
-Would you like a tour?
好啊
Sure. That'd be great.
可以帮我鹱∫徽舐穑
Could you hold this for a sec?
可以
Yeah, sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
你今次遇上情场劲敌
Man, you got some serious competition.
不要傻
Please.
-必定是有钱仔
-收声
-And l'll bet he's really rich too.
-Shut up.
-是谁？
-是泰利擦臣
-Who is it?
-Terry Rapson here.
抱歉在凌晨骚扰你
Sorry to call you so early.
不要紧，什么事？
No, professor, it's all right.
What is it?
我们发现了一些不寻常
而令人担心的情况
Well, we've found something extraordinary.
Extraordinary and disturbing, that is.
你记得你在新德里说过地极冰融K
You recall what you said in New Delhi
about how polar melting...
-可能干扰北大西洋的海流吗？
-记得
-...might disrupt the North Atlantic Current?
-Yes.
这K
Well...
这情况正在发生
...l think it's happening.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
前几日我们探测到大西洋水温K
One of our NOMAD buoys registered
a 1 3-degree drop...
下降了十三度，我发了电邮通知你
...in surface temperature.
I've sent you an e-mail.
等一等
Hold on.
起初以为是个别仪器失灵
At first we thought it was a malfunction.
不过有四个仪器传来同一资料
But there are four more across
the North Atlantic showing the same thing.
这真的是难以置信
This is unbelievable.
你预测过会出现
You predicted it would happen.
但不是在我们这一代出现，太快了
Yes, but not in our lifetime.
This is too fast.
只有你的电脑模拟程式才能够预测到K
There are no forecast models
remotely capable...
气候会变成这样
...of plotting this scenario, except yours.
我的模拟程式是用来研究史前气候
My model is a reconstruction
of a prehistoric climate shift.
不是用来预测
lt's not a forecast model.
但已是最接近的模拟程式
It's the closest thing we have.
这种情况从未出现过
Nothing like this has ever
happened before.
起码一万年来未曾出现
At least not in the last 1 0,000 years.
正如我昨天估计
咙风娜兰妮带来巨浪
As I predicted yesterday, the swell
off Hurricane Noelani is incredible.
比我想像中更巨大的巨浪，看吧
These waves are even bigger
than I imagined. Just take a look.
-你不是应该在监察气候吗？
-这里是洛杉矶，天气是十年如一日的
-Shouldn't you be monitoring the weather?
-This is L.A. What weather?
等一等，那是什么声音？
Wait. What's that noise?
什么声音？
What noise?
很快回来
Honey, l'll be right back.
各海滩现已封闭，海浪大到连K
The Coast Guard closed the beaches,
as waves have grown too big for....
-洛杉矶气候中心
-我是汤美
-L.A. Weather Center.
-It's Tommy.
我正在忙，什么事？
l'm in the middle of something, Tommy.
What do you need?
正在落r，高尔夫球那样大的r
There's hail the size of golf balls
coming down here.
加州沿岸的低压K
A low-pressure system along
the California coast...
正在洛杉矶盘地形成大气旋
...is creating a cyclonic system
across the L.A. Basin.
-喂？
-波士，扭开天气台
-Yeah?
-Boss, turn on The Weather Channel.
-我们要发出龙卷风警告
-你在说什么？
-I think we have to issue a tornado warning.
-What are you talking about?
洛杉矶风力时速超过K
Palmdale and Lancaster are reporting
wind speeds in excess....
-等一等
-这些情况极不寻常
-Hold on a second.
-Conditions highly unusual for California.
要制造预测模拟程式，需要什么？
We're building a forecast model,
we need-- What?
接驳去电脑主机两三日
Priority access to the mainframe
for two days, maybe three.
-是吗？
-须立即接驳
-Oh, is that it? Anything else?
-We need it immediately.
我认为你发碰K
l would say that
you've lost your mind...
不过你发惯碰
...but you've been this way
for the past 20 years.
-汤，这是重要的
-你在制造什么预测模拟程式？
-Tom, this is important.
-What's this forecast model you're building?
这位珍纳是太空总署咙风专家
Janet Tokada, this is Jack Hall.
Janet's a hurricane specialist with NASA.
积是古气象学家
我完全不知道他想搞什么
Jack's a paleoclimatologist, and l have
absolutely no idea what he's up to.
卜加！发生什么事？
Booker. What's going on here?
洛杉矶发出龙卷风警告
They just issued a tornado warning
in Los Angeles.
我们在洛杉矶现场直播
Breaking news as we prepare to go live
to Los Angeles.
多个报告都显示
该区天象极度反常
Mixed reports are coming in about some
extreme weather occurring in the area.
现在接去我们在洛杉矶的霍士分台
Okay, we're now going live
to our Fox affiliate in Los Angeles.
我们在直升机上，你听到吗？
We have live coverage now from our Fox 1 1
chopper. Are you there, Bart?
我听到，龙卷风形成得好快K
Yes, l'm here. These tornados
are forming so fast--
-巴特！
-什么？不得了
-Bart!
-What? Oh! Oh, my God.
丽莎，你接收得到影像吗？
Lisa, are you getting this on camera?
龙卷风把好莱坞大标志卷走
This tornado just erased
the Hollywood sign.
大招牌被卷走，卷成碎片
The Hollywood sign is gone.
It's just shredded.
巴特，你见到什么？
有没有人受伤？
Bart, what can you see? ls anyone hurt?
机会很大，这里满目H箔
l wouldn't be surprised.
There is so much damage.
有些人在拍照！
And there are people down there
taking pictures.
你们做什么？快找地方躲！
Hey, what the hell are you guys doing?
Go for cover!
不可以留在这里！快走！
You can't stay here! Get out of here!
两股龙卷风正吹袭洛杉矶国际机场
What you're seeing are two actual tornados
striking Los Angeles lnternational Airport.
现在二合一，合成一大股龙卷风
Wait. lt looks like they've joined
and formed one large tornado.
-汤美！
-惨啦！
-Tommy!
-Oh, my God!
惨！
Holy shit!
敦促各位观众避开K
I'd like to urge all of our viewers
to stay away....
-谢夫，你在哪里？
-在兰街与葡萄街交界
-Jeff, where are you?
-l'm on Yucca and vine.
-我正要回来
-你上了电视，龙卷风就在你附近
-l'm on my way.
-You're on Tv. You're in the middle of it.
蹋〔遥
God! Oh, my God!
快些离开！
You gotta get out of there, man.
巴士刚刚跌落在保时捷上
That bus just got dropped
on top of that Porsche!
但愿车里没有人
Oh, my God.
I hope no one was in that car.
现在才开始收看的观众K
For our national audience
just joining us now...
我们正在现场直播
洛杉矶市区的情形，汤美？
...we are going live to downtown
Los Angeles right now. Tommy?
我后面是龙卷风
If you look over there behind me,
that's a tornado.
对，洛杉矶竟然出现龙卷风
Yes, a twister in Los Angeles.
是众多肆虐本市的龙卷风之一
lt's one of many tornados
that are destroying our city.
那里有另一股
那是洛杉矶的空中轮锅线
There's another one.
That's the Los Angeles skyline.
R利！好巨型！前所未见
It's unbelievable! It's huge!
I've never seen anything like it.
发生什么事？
What's happening?
仿佛是一场K
lt looks like some sort of...
大恶梦，只是现在恶梦成真
...huge, horrific, terrifying nightmare,
only this is the real thing.
我正在看
Yes, l'm looking at it right now.
-对
-发生什么事？
-Yes, it is.
-What's happening?
我再打给你
l'll call you back.
总统先生，洛杉矶给龙卷风摧毁
Mr. President, Los Angeles has been
devastated by a series of tornados.
除此之外
民航局请你批准所有航机停航
On top of that, the FAA wants your
approval to suspend all air traffic.
-你觉得我们应该怎样做？
-原因未明前K
-What do you think we should do?
-Until we can figure it out...
我们没有选择的余地
...l don't think we have
much choice, sir.
这是洛杉矶商业区的残余部分
What you're seeing is what's left
of downtown Los Angeles.
我刚同我妈通过电话
Hey, man, l just got off the phone
with my mom.
对不起，真的很对不起
但我们要转台
Excuse me, you guys. l'm really sorry,
but we need to change the channel.
民航局下令中止美国所有的航空交通
The FAA has grounded
all air traffic in the United States.
不幸地，有两架飞机来不及降落K
Unfortunately, the order came too late
for two planes...
在中西部遇上猛烈气流而坠毁
...brought down by severe turbulence
in the Midwest.
-第一班机是K
-所谓“十亿份之一”
-The first flight....
-So much for ''one in a billion.''
好，大家听着
All right. All right, listen up, everybody.
Listen up, please.
我们要做的事情很多
但时间无多K
We've got a lot of work to do,
and we don't have much time...
大家开工，华士丁？
...so let's get started, please. vorsteen?
我们的短期预测模拟程式无用
All our grid models are worthless.
我不觉得模拟程式会有帮助
l don't think grid models
are gonna be a lot of help here.
加拿大人的报告说
北极出现巨大的大气环流
Canadians report tremendous circulation
moving from the Arctic.
西伯利亚笼罩着前所未见的低压
ln Siberia, there's a low-pressure system
never before seen.
澳洲刚经历有史以来最猛烈讳风
And Australia just saw
the strongest typhoon ever recorded.
-这些现象都互有关联？
-有可能
-These things are interconnected?
-We have to consider the possibility.
只有太阳才能影响全球气候
The only force strong enough to affect
global weather is the sun.
-太空总署有什么意见？
-我们已经查过
-What's NASA have to say?
-We've already checked.
太阳辐射输出正常
Solar output is normal.
-北大西洋海流呢？
-怎样？
-What about the North Atlantic Current?
-What about it?
我昨晚同赫兰中心的擦臣教授谈过
l got a call last night from Professor Rapson
at the Hedland Center.
他认为海流有变
He thinks the current has changed.
怎可能？
Oh, come on, Jack.
How could that be?
海流是靠Q和淡水的
微妙平衡来维持正常
The current depends upon a balance
of salt and freshwater.
海流是靠Q和淡水的
微妙平衡来维持正常
The current depends upon a balance
of salt and freshwater.
-我们都知道
-没错K
-We all know that.
-Yes...
但无人知道由于地极冰融K
...but no one knows how much freshwater
has been dumped into the ocean...
引致多少淡水倾倒入海
...because of melting polar ice.
我相信脱Q作用
已经到达了一个危险的地步
l think we've hit a critical
desalinization point.
这就是造成这样极端的天气的原因
lt would explain what's driving
this extreme weather.
赫兰中心的数据相当可靠
Hedland had some
pretty convincing data.
他们要求我把数据输入
我的模拟程式，预测未来情况
They've asked me to feed it into my
paleoclimate model to track the next events.
你的意思是，反常气候会持续？
Are you suggesting these weather
anomalies are gonna continue?
不仅持续，而且每况愈下
Not just continue. Get worse.
我相信我们将会面临气候剧变
l think we're on the verge
of a major climate shift.
你会怎样告诉总统？
What are you gonna tell
the Administration?
-你认为呢？
-从速作长远准备
-What do you expect me to tell them?
-The government has to make preparations.
-这些全部只是你的理论
-给我使用电脑主机去证实吧
-You have a theory.
-Give me the mainframe. l'll prove it.
不
No.
给你四十八小时
You have 48 hours.
-贺教授
-是
-Professor Hall.
-Yes.
-我相信你的理论可能正确
-我们边走边谈
-l think your theory may be correct.
-Walk with me.
几个星期前
我见到有史以来最强的咙风
Just a few weeks ago, l monitored
the strongest hurricane on record.
冰r、龙卷风，一切ê
The hail, the tornados, it all fits.
你的模拟程式
可不可以计算风暴情况？
Can your model factor in
storm scenarios?
-我们没有时间
-我可以帮手
-We haven't had the time.
-Well, maybe l can help.
-欢迎你加入
-多谢
-Welcome aboard.
-Thanks.
你好，我叫泽逊
Hi, l'm Jason.
-你好
-Hi.
彼得的电脑断层扫描结果有未？
Do you have Peter's CT scan results?
有了，治疗后，肿瘤收缩了两成
Yeah. The treatments
shrunk the tumor 20 percent.
-他的视觉怎样？
-没有改善
-ls his eyesight better today?
-No. No change.
-彼得，你今日觉得怎样？
-好一点
-Hi, Peter. How are you doing today?
-A little better.
好
Good.
让我听听
Let me listen here.
你读得到吗？
Can you read that?
读不到，不过从图片记得内容
No, but l remember the story
from the pictures.
你记得？
You do?
我妈以前读过给我听
My mother used to read it to me.
你非常勇敢，她必定很以你为荣
She must be very proud of you.
You've been such a brave, big boy.
-多谢
-不要客气
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-给你的
-多谢
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
你一口气工作了廿四小时
Jack, you've been working
for 24 hours straight.
只有你一个没有休息过
You're the only one
who hasn't taken a break.
或者我可以闭目养神一会
Maybe l'll try to shut my eyes
for a while.
有结果通知我
Call me when you get the results.
他总是这样拼搏？
Frank, is he always so obsessive?
-总是
-是
-Yeah.
-Yes.
从不轻松一点？
Does he ever lighten up?
-从不轻松
-从不
-Not really.
-No.
-你们合作了多久？
-法兰自从石器时代K
-How long have you been working together?
-Well, Frank's been working with him...
已经同他拍档
我只焙了两年奴仆生活
...since the Stone Age, but l've only
had to endure two years of servitude.
积
Jack.
积，结果出来了
Jack, we got the results.
六至八个月？不可能
Six to eight months? That can't be.
不是以月计，是以星期计
That time scale isn't in months.
lt's in weeks.
广泛水浸令到很多地方封闭
包括两条隧道
Flooding has caused numerous closures,
including the Lincoln and Holland Tunnels.
学校水管旧了，沟渠排不走雨水
The plumbing in the school is really old.
With this rain, the sewage got stopped up.
你住在哪里？
Where are you staying?
他们正在替我们找地方住
They're finding a place for us
with kids here.
你可以在明日之前回来吗？
You can't get home any sooner
than tomorrow?
可以的话，我会尽早K
Well, look, Dad, l would if l could,
you know. lt's just....
这里臭得厉害
This smell is unbearable, Dad.
不要再讲笑
我要你立即回来
Stop kidding around! l want you home.
我去搭火车
Dad, I'll be on the train.
不要担心，我会设法
Do me a favor. Just don't worry about me.
l'll figure it out.
好吧，阿仔，明天见
All right, son. l'll see you tomorrow.
森
Hey, Sam, guess what?
我们有地方住
We got a place to stay.
好极
Great.
恶劣天气暂时未抵达首都
但是首都居民不敢迓K
So far, the terrible weather hasn't hit D.C.,
but local residents aren't taking chances...
大家忙于准备K
...as people stock up for what is already
being billed as...
-应付最恶劣风季
-你最好有十足把握
-...the worst storm season on record.
-Better be sure.
-我不想被抄鱿鱼
-你见过模拟程式
-My ass is on the line.
-You saw the model.
我希望是错的
And l hope to God it's wrong.
-副总统先生
-汤
-Mr. vice President.
-Tom.
-你认识贺教授
-是，我们见过面
-You know Professor Hall.
-Yes, we've met.
贺教授有些资料
我觉得你应该看一看
Professor Hall has some information
l think you should look at.
从我们的模拟程式
分析出来的结果
We just got these results
from our simulation model.
-我们可以解释天气恶劣的原因
-我迟些再看
-They explain what's causing this weather.
-l'll read it later.
-我要同危急处理局局长开会K
-这是非常危急的
-l have to meet with the director of FEMA--
-This is very urgent.
六至八星期内
气候会发生剧变
Our climate is changing violently. lt will
happen over the next six to eight weeks.
你说过会在一百年后发生
You said this wouldn't happen
for another 1 00 years.
-我错了
-假如你现在又错呢？
-l was wrong.
-Well, suppose you're wrong this time.
我都希望我是错的
但你必定察觉到全球的反常气候变化
l wish l were, but you're aware
of what's happening everywhere.
我们正在做应变功夫
你还想我们做什么？
We're making all the necessary preparations
for this storm. What more do you expect?
你要开始考虑大规模疏散
You have to start thinking about
large-scale evacuations right now.
尤其是北部各州
Especially in the Northern states.
-疏散？
-对
-Evacuations?
-Yes.
发神经吗？我要走了
Have you lost your mind, Hall?
l have to go.
副总统先生！
现在还不采取行动，就会太迟！
Mr. vice President! lf we don't act now,
it's going to be too late.
我们走吧
Come on, Jack.
多谢带我们来
Thanks for bringing us here.
来纽约，不可错过自然史博物馆
l couldn't let you leave New York without
seeing the Natural History Museum.
当然不可
这里是全世界最大的毛公仔展览馆
Of course not. lt's a fine collection
of stuffed animals.
看
Hey, guys, check this out.
本长毛象在西伯利亚被发现时
尸体完整K
''The body of this mammoth was found
perfectly preserved in the Siberian tundra...
口里胃里依然有食物K
...with food still in its mouth
and stomach...
显示它在食食物的时候，一俐间冷僵
...indicating that it froze instantly
while grazing.''
至今，英国与北欧下雪K
It's been 24 hours now since the snow
started falling across the British Isles...
已经下了廿四小时
我们并不知道雪几时会停
...and over Northern Europe.
It shows no signs of letting up.
不K不要担心
No, no, no.
You've got to stop worrying. No, no.
只不过是落雪
我们有很多鲁食用品
lt's fine. We've got plenty of supplies.
We're just snowed in.
对，没有问题的
Yeah. No, it's all right. lt's all right.
你不要走开，我没事
No, you stay where you are.
l'll be fine.
我也爱你，拜拜
Yeah, l love you too. Okay, bye.
-珍纳怎样？
-没事
-Hey. How's Jeanette?
-Oh, fine.
渡轮刚刚泊岸
The ferry just landed.
西班牙天气应该很好，可惜我没机会去
Must be nice in Spain.
Wish l was there.
救援直升机已经出发，准备K
An elite RAF search-and-rescue team
has been deployed by helicopter...
把皇室人员载到安全地点
...to airlift the royal family to safety.
-直升机会来接我们吗？
-不大可能
-Yeah, you think they'll come get us?
-Not likely.
幸好我们有发电机、茶叶同饼干
Luckily we've got our own genny,
enough tea and biscuits to sink a ship.
应该没事
Oh, we'll be fine.
只要厕所水不倒流
As long as the loo
doesn't back up again.
我们什么也看不到
保持方向和速度
We've got zero visibility.
Maintain heading and speed.
-我们的方向呢？
-是035
-What's our heading?
-035, sir.
离皇室堡约四十公里
Approximately 40 kilometers
from Balmoral Castle.
我们看不到你们
We've lost visual contact with you.
-咪表不可能正确
-风速降至零
-This gauge can't be right.
-Wind speed has dropped to zero.
一堵垂直云墙正在形成
We have vertical walls
of cirrus cloud formations.
-究竟发生什么事？
-燃油在凝固！
-What the hell is going on?
-The bloody fuel lines are starting to freeze.
左引擎压力下降！转速下跌！
Port engine pressure is dropping.
The rotor rpm is dropping.
右边的引擎也停止转动
We've got a flameout on
the starboard side as well.
准备紧急降落
Prepare for crash landing.
选用紧急燃料
Select emergency fuel.
稳定点！
Come on, you bastard!
Come on!
这是机密消息
What l'm about to say
is supposed to be confidential.
这是机密消息
What l'm about to say
is supposed to be confidential.
几个钟头前
三架直升机在苏格兰失事
Several hours ago, three helicopters
went down over Scotland.
原因是燃油在输油管内凝结
They crashed because the fuel
in their lines froze.
-什么温度才K？
-华氏零下150度
-At what temperature does--?
-Negative 1 50 degrees Fahrenheit.
是查出来的
We had to look it up.
气温急剧直线下降
The temperature dropped
phenomenally fast.
陆地上，大家未落车已经冻僵
On the ground, people froze before
they could get out of their cars even.
陆地上，大家未落车已经冻僵
On the ground, people froze before
they could get out of their cars even.
我想看两小时前苏格兰的卫星照片
Can you get a satellite picture
of Scotland two hours ago?
数据有很多K
We've got mountains of data...
但电脑不够快处理
可不可以帮帮忙？
...but nowhere near enough computer
power to analyze it. Can you help us?
即管把资料传送过来
我们会尽力
Send us what you got.
We'll do our best.
多谢你，拜拜
Thanks, Jack. Bye for now.
这是温度骤降下的苏格兰
This is Scotland at the time
the temperature dropped.
这东西看来像咙风
This thing looks just like a hurricane.
可是咙风不会在陆上形成
Only hurricanes don't form over land.
-你好，少爷！
-夏劳
-Good evening, sir.
-Hey, Harold.
-多谢，域陀，明早见
-是
-Thanks, victor. See you in the morning.
-Right, sir.
-可怕的天气
-的确
-Terrible weather.
-Tell me about it.
哗
Wow.
你住在这里？
You live here?
只是在周末
Just on the weekends.
这是我爸的家
但是他很少来K
lt's my dad's place.
He's kind of never around, so....
他在哪里？
Where is he?
同我继母到欧洲滑雪
Skiing in Europe with my stepmom.
这是你同你弟弟？
ls this you and your brother?
对，我们在踩单车旅行
Yeah, that's when we took
a bike trip together.
大雨已经下了三日
lt's been raining like this
for three days now.
来，快
Come on, hurry up.
我只是避避雨
l'm just standing here.
不可以
You can't stay here.
反正我都不是太喜欢这一区
l never liked this neighborhood anyway.
中区总站秩序大乱
It's a mob scene here
at Grand Central Station.
过半月台水浸，火车停止服务
Over half the platforms are flooded and
service has been suspended on all trains.
飞机仍然停航
而火车也停止服务K
With planes still grounded
and trains now out of service...
这真是坏消息K
...that's bad news for the....
司机快来接我，要送你们去火车站吗？
victor's coming to pick me up.
You guys want a ride to the train station?
已经不用去
Not anymore.
加拿大东南部，水位急升廿五尺
In Nova Scotia earlier today the ocean
rose by 25 feet in a matter of seconds.
最可怕的情况终于出现
What we have feared for the past
few days has indeed happened.
两股来自北极的冷锋竟然K
The cold front moving from the Arctic...
在加拿大合成一个风暴K
...has created an enormous
storm system in Canada...
虽然难以致信
但它越来越像一个热带咙风K
...which, incredible as it sounds,
looks more like a tropical hurricane....
我要去接弟弟
你们要我送你一程吗？
l gotta go pick up my little brother.
Do you guys want a ride?
-他在哪里？
-费城的寄宿学校
-Where is he?
-He's in a boarding school in Philadelphia.
假如这气候南下K
If this system moves south...
风暴潮将会危及整个东海床
...we could see a wind-driven storm surge
threaten the entire Eastern Seaboard.
好，拜拜
Okay, bye.
司机在第五街遇上塞车，驶不动
victor's stuck in traffic
over on Fifth Avenue.
如果我们去那处找他
比较容易离开这个城市
lt'll be easier to head out of town
if we meet him over there.
-行路去？
-这样的天气我不去
-You mean walk?
-No, not in this.
我们应该行楼梯
We should take the stairs.
我们住顶楼
We're on the top floor.
大概只可行楼梯
l guess we're walking.
或者我们不应该出去
Maybe we should just stay here.
小姐说得对
l think the young lady is right.
不，我们要回家去
No. We need to get home.
凯萨，过来
Hey, Cesar, come here.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
所有狼都不见了！
The wolves, they're gone.
现在的情形是K
Just to give you an idea
of the situation...
天气的情况急转直下
...which seems to be becoming worse
with each passing minute:
四处几乎成为泽国
At the moment, we have flooding
in most parts of the island.
交通几乎瘫喝
原因是曼哈顿大部分的地方都停电K
We've got traffic snarl-ups
because the electricity is now out...
没有交通灯
...to almost every part of Manhattan.
No traffic signals.
起码出现两百宗交通意外
Car accidents, at least two hundred.
下曼哈顿寸步难行
And lower Manhattan, we've been told,
is virtually inaccessible.
可不可以替我打给我妈？
Can you call Mom?
Will you please phone her for me?
喂
Hey.
狗不可以进来
That dog can't come in here.
可是外面下着倾盘大雨！
Come on, man. lt's pouring out there.
我不理，看标示吧
l don't care. Read the sign.
（禁止饮食、禁携宠物）
这是公共图书馆啊
lt's supposed to be a public library.
快，这边
Come on, guys, this way.
你好论尽
Excuse me. Your bad.
千五元的雨衣却挡不到雨！
Goddamn 1 500-dollar
waterproof raincoat.
-好心你收声
-肯定到处都是老鼠
-Please, shut up, man.
-There must be rats everywhere.
因为这里是纽约
That's because it's New York.
喂！喂！
Hey! Hey!
-开门
-不载客
-Open up, big papa.
-lt's out of service.
不载客！
lt's out of service.
-给你一百元
-不用
-l'll give you a 1 00 dollars.
-You don't have to do that.
收下来吧，两百元
No, really. 200 dollars.
l won't have it.
我喜欢坐巴士，认真过瘾
God, l love buses. This is so much fun.
This is gonna be the bomb.
喂？
Hello?
-我联络不到我的司机，电话收不到
-发神经才在街上走
-l can't reach my driver. No signal.
-This is insane.
不可能可以驾车
回你家吧
We're not gonna be able to drive.
We should go back.
-我赞成
-你讲笑吗？我们要向高处走！
-Yeah, l vote for that.
-Are you kidding? We have to get higher!
跟我来
Come on.
上图书馆去
Up to the library.
冷静
Calm down.
我听不明白你说什么
l can't understand what you're saying.
冷静点，我会帮你们走出来
lf you stay calm, ma'am,
l'll get you out.
门卡死了！
The door is jammed!
我不懂法文！
l don't speak French!
罗拉呢？
Hey, where's Laura?
-刚才明明在这里
-那里！看到吗？
-She was just right there.
-She's right there! Right there, see?
她在做什么？
What is she doing?
叫他们掩着眼睛！
Tell them to cover their eyes.
有堵水墙向纽约冲过来
各位K
There is a wall of water coming towards
New York City. Everybody--
-什么事？
-她的手袋在的士上，他们的护照
-What?
-Her bag's in the cab. Their passports.
没有时间回去拿了
Forget about it.
-我去
-走吧
-l'll get it for her.
-Come on.
我的K
Oh, my....
罗拉！
Laura!
-森
-不要去！拜仁，不
-Sam.
-No! Brian, no!
罗拉！罗拉，看！
Laura! Laura, look!
赶快！跑！
Come on. Come!
赶快！
Come on!
森！
Sam!
教授
Professor.
多谢
Thank you.
-是尼仔的作品吗？
-尼仔不再划火柴公仔
-ls that Neville's handiwork?
-Neville's way beyond stick figures.
-他已经六岁了
-是吗？
-He's 6 already.
-Oh.
这是我第二个孙大卫的杰作
No, this masterpiece belongs
to my second grandson, David.
想不到尼仔已经六岁
God. l can't believe Neville's 6 already.
小孩子快高长大
You won't believe how fast they grow.
阿积找你
l've got Jack Hall on the phone.
他们已经处埋好数据
They've run the data we've sent them.
给你
Here he is.
你可以模拟热循环吗？
Jack, were you able to recreate
the thermal cycle?
可以，风暴K
Yes. The storm's rotation...
把超冷却空气
从对流层扯下来
...is pulling super-cooled air all the way
down from the upper troposphere.
可是空气未着陆前
不是应该变暖的吗？
But shouldn't the air warm up
before it reaches ground level?
下降得太快，来不及变暖
It should. But it doesn't.
The air's descending too rapidly.
这是不是个别情况？
ls this an isolated incident?
恐怕不是
l'm afraid not.
除了苏格兰之外
我们再发现了两个超级单体风暴
We've located two supercells
in addition to the one over Scotland.
一个在加拿大北面K
One over Northern Canada...
另一个在西伯利亚
...and another one over Siberia.
估计得到风暴路向吗？
And do we know their projected paths?
可以
Yes.
同我们早前所估计的，快得很多
Our previous estimates of six to
eight weeks weren't even close.
这个风暴将会令地球改头换面
This one storm is going to change
the face of our planet.
这是单体风暴形成廿四小时后的情形
Here's a projection of 24 hours out.
形成四十八小时后
This is 48 hours out.
七至十日后K
And in seven to 1 0 days....
当风暴过后K
When this storm is over...
我们会进入新冰河时期
...we'll be in a new ice age.
惨
My God.
教授K
Professor...
趁有机会走吧
...it's time you got out of there.
恐怕我们已经错过机会了
l'm afraid that time has
come and gone, my friend.
我们可以怎样做？
What can we do?
救得一个得一个
Save as many as you can.
积K
Jack...
纽约出了事
...something's happened in New York.
没有电，我已经在这里一整日了
No, the power is out.
l've been in here all day.
-谁要帮忙？
-这里
-Who needs help?
-Here. Over here.
什么事？
What?
这是最后一条，好好享受
This is the last one. Enjoy it.
贪心鬼
Greedy.
线路现正繁忙
All circuits are busy at this time.
多谢你回来找我
Listen, thanks for coming back for me.
你很勇敢
lt was really brave.
我要把手袋还给她了
l guess l better return her bag.
森？
Sam?
向她表明心迹吧
Just tell her how you feel.
好
Yeah.
-你联不联络到你的弟弟？
-电话打不通
-Did you reach your little brother yet?
-No, there's still no service.
死鬼流动电话
Damn cell phones.
请问，上层有没有收费电话？
Excuse me. Are there any
pay phones on the upper floors?
没有K
No, no, no.
-但阁楼有几部
-太好了
-There are some on the mezzanine.
-Great.
-但我估阁楼已被水淹没了！
-你去哪里？已经停电了
-But l think it's underwater.
-Where you going? Power's out.
旧式电话用电话线的电
Older payphones draw power
directly from the line.
国家海洋和大气局
各部门的主管将会举行紧急会议K
There will be an emergency meeting
of all NOAA department heads....
我一直尝试联络阿森
Oh, God. l've been trying to reach Sam.
我也是
So have l.
打给你又打不通
l tried to call
and couldn't get you.
这里天下大乱，跟我来
lt's been a madhouse here. Come on.
你肯定要这样做？
Are you sure about this?
打得通
lt works.
我喜欢那张照片
l love that picture.
我也喜欢
Yeah, so do l.
在哪里拍的？
Where was that taken?
迈阿米
Miami.
我在哪里？我记不起我有去过
Well, where was l?
l don't remember that trip.
森，我和我的家姐一起去
你在阿拉斯加K
Sam and l went with my sister.
You were in Alaska...
做研究
...doing research on your doctorate.
记得他小时候是怎样吗？
Remember what he was like
when he was that age?
口头禅是“再一次”
Everything was ''one more.''
再讲一次故事，再骑一次牛牛
“再一次，爸爸”
One more bedtime story. One more ride
on my shoulders. ''One more, Daddy.''
积！森打电话来，四线
Jack. Sam's on the phone. Line four.
-森？
-爸爸！
-Sam?
-Dad!
-你在哪里？
-我没事，在公共图书馆内
-Where are you? Are you all right?
-l'm all right. We're at the Public Library.
-阿森，是妈呀，你平安就好了！
-妈
-Sam, it's Mom. l'm so happy you're okay.
-Mom.
可以向罗拉和拜仁家报平安吗？
Can you call Laura and Brian's parents
and tell them we're all right?
好，没问题
Yes, of course.
-阿森，那是什么声音？
-阿森
-Sam, what's that noise?
-Sam?
阿森
Sam?
爸，外面发生了什么事？
What is going on out there, Dad?
阿森
Sam. Sam, listen to me.
小心听着
Listen very carefully.
不要南下
Forget what l said about heading south.
太迟了，气候只会愈来愈恶劣
lt's too late.
The storm is gonna get worse.
会出现一股庞大的暴风雪
中间有风眼
It's gonna turn into a massive blizzard with
an eye in the center, like a huge hurricane.
非常冻，冻到可以将人即时冻死
Only the air will be so cold,
you could freeze to death in seconds.
阿森？
Sam?
-我们应该怎样做？
-听着，阿仔
-Well, what should we do?
-Listen to me, son.
不要出外
Do not go outside.
有什么烧什么，尽量取暖
和耐心等待
Burn what you can to stay warm,
and try to wait it out.
我会去救你，你明白吗？
我会去救你
l will come for you. Do you understand me?
l will come for you.
阿森
Sam?
-阿森，回来！
-阿森
-Sam, come back!
-Sam?
阿森，你听到没有？
Sam, did you hear me?
你听到没有？
Did you hear me?
阿森
Sam?
-告诉我他会没事K
-他会平安
-Tell me he's gonna be okay--
-He's gonna be all right.
他会平安，你明不明白？
He's gonna be all right,
you understand?
还以为你已经浸死
l thought you'd drowned.
去找些干衣服给你换
Let's find some dry clothes for you.
Come on.
北极探险装备放在哪里？
Where'd you store the arctic gear?
你去不到纽约
You can't make it to New York, Jack.
我试过在雪中走得更远
l've walked that far before in the snow.
今次情形不同
This is not the same.
这次情况不同！露丝，告诉他吧
Jack, this is not the same.
Lucy, tell him.
我非去不可
l have to do this.
我明白
l know.
我的手在发抖K
My hands are shak--
-发抖
-给你
-Shaking.
-That's okay. Here.
过来
Here. Come here.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
用我体温替你取暖
l'm using my body heat to warm you.
如果四肢的血，太快流向心脏K
lf we let the blood from your arms and legs
rush back to your heart too quickly...
心脏会停顿
...your heart could fail.
你从哪里学来的？
Where did you learn that?
上健康课时肯听书就学得到
Some of us were actually
paying attention in health class.
觉得怎样？
How are you feeling?
好得多
Much better.
法兰告诉了我森的事
Frank told me about Sam.
我不会阻止你
但你先要替我做一件事
l'm not gonna try to talk you out of going,
but there's something l need first.
你要向白宫解释你的预测
You have to explain your results
to the Administration.
-我已经试过
-今次不同
-l already tried that, Tom.
-l know. lt'll be different.
你会向总统直接汇报
You're gonna brief the president directly.
-再没有衣服了吗？
-没有了
-ls that the last of it?
-Pretty much.
好
Okay.
找到一部收音机，不过失灵
We also found this radio,
but l don't think it works.
让我看看
Let me see it.
阿宝，别吵
Buddha, keep quiet.
这里本来不准你来
You ain't even supposed
to be in here anyway.
这边
Come on, guys.
我的天
Oh, my God.
风暴会持续到K
The basic rule of storms
is they continue...
气候回复平衡
...until the imbalance that
created them is corrected.
全球气候会面目全非
ln this case, we're talking
about a global realignment.
超级风暴会持续七至十日
This superstorm will last
seven to 1 0 days.
然后，北半球会变成冰雪世界
When it's over, ice and snow will cover
the entire Northern Hemisphere.
冰雪会把阳光反射
The ice and snow will reflect sunlight.
大气层会重新稳定，不过K
The Earth's atmosphere will restabilize...
气温会接近上次冰河时期
...with an average temperature
close to that of the last lce Age.
我们可以怎样做？
Well, what can we do about this?
尽量南下
Head as far south as possible.
那并不好笑，教授
That is not amusing, professor.
你建议国民去哪里？
Where do you suggest they go?
愈南愈安全
The farther south they go,
the safer they'll be.
去德州，去没水浸的佛罗里达
最好去墨西哥
Texas. Parts of Florida that aren't
flooded. Mexico would be best.
墨西哥？你只管科学好了
政策由我们来决定
Mexico? Maybe you should stick
to science and leave policy to us.
我们试过那个方案
Well, we tried that approach.
为时未晚时劝你，你听不入耳
You didn't want to hear about the science
when it could have made a difference.
教授，你有什么实质提议？
What exactly are you proposing, professor?
疏散那条线以南的人
Evacuate everyone south of that line.
北部的人呢？
What about the people in the North?
已经太迟
l'm afraid it's too late for them.
他们一出外K
lf they go outside...
会冻死于风雪里
...the storm will kill them.
到这地步K
At this point...
他们最好躲在室内
...their best chance is to stay inside.
看看能否避过这场灾劫
Try to ride it out.
听天由命
Pray.
你觉得他会怎样做？
What do you think he'll do?
不知道
l don't know.
积K
Jack...
多谢你K
...thanks...
祝你好运
...and good luck.
我也祝你好运
You too.
我们都需要运气
We're all gonna need it.
不能因为那科学家一面之词
而疏散半个国家的人民
We can't evacuate half the country because
one scientist thinks the climate is shifting.
-犹豫不决，只会死得更多人
-北方的人呢？
-Every minute we delay costs lives.
-What about the other half of the country?
假如贺教授说得对K
lf Professor Hall is right
about this storm...
派兵北上救人只是送死
...sending troops north will
create more victims.
我们要救可以救的人
We need to save the people
we can right now.
就像战场上救伤K
We take the same approach in triage
on the battlefield.
有必要壮士断臂K
Sometimes it's necessary
to make difficult choices--
我不认为有必要放弃一半国民
l don't accept abandoning
half the country as necessary.
如果你肯早点听他忠告
就没有必要了
Maybe if you listened sooner,
it wouldn't be.
他在首都安安全全
Bullshit. lt's easy for him
to suggest this plan.
-才夸夸其谈
-他儿子在曼哈顿
-He's safely here in Washington.
-His son is in Manhattan.
你未质疑他用心前，先紧记这点
l thought you should know before
you start questioning his motives.
我们采用贺积的方案
We're going to follow Hall's plan.
-将军
-总统？
-General.
-Sir?
下令国卫军疏散南部各州
Give the order for the National Guard
to evacuate Southern states.
知道，总统
Yes, sir.
慧濉K
vivian...
接去我太太
...get me my wife.
对不起，汽油快要用完
Sorry, mates,
but we're just about out of petrol.
喂
Hey.
可不可以K
ls there any chance...
用这个K
...that it'll run...
做燃料？
...on this?
你发神经吗？
Are you mad?
这是十二年威士忌！
That's a 1 2-year-old Scotch.
各位
Gentlemen.
向英国干杯
To England.
向全人类干杯
To mankind.
向曼联干杯
To Manchester United.
可惜K
l just....
可惜我看不到他长大
l just wish l could have seen
him grow up. You know?
重要的是他会长大
The important thing is he will grow up.
阿门
Amen.
或者应该找人帮你修理
Maybe you should have somebody
help you with that.
我是电子K
Sir, l am president of the Electronics Club...
数学、象棋学会会长
...the Math Club and the Chess Club.
论书虫，我认第一，无人敢认第二
Now, if there's a bigger nerd in here,
please, point him out.
那就不打扰你了
l'll just leave you alone
to work on it, okay?
阿宝，快点出恭
Come on, Buddha, come on.
Do your business.
趁附近没有人
Look, there's nobody around.
我转过身去，保证不偷看
You know what? l'll turn around.
l won't look. l promise.
什么事？
What?
出面有人
Hey, man, there's people out there.
我带狗去散步
l was walking my dog.
有好几百个
他们在雪地上走
There's hundreds of them.
They're walking on the snow.
他们去哪里？
Where they all going?
趁还来得及，离开纽约
They're getting out of the city
before it's too late.
大家安静点
All right, everybody. Quiet down.
谁同外界讲过手提电话？
When was the last time anyone
got a signal on a cell phone?
我在曼菲斯的亲杯说
l got through to my cousin
in Memphis an hour ago.
人人南下
They're being evacuated to the South.
我们也应该走
We should get moving too.
我们可以在冰上行走
The water is frozen over
enough to walk on.
趁雪未太深出发吧！
We should get going before
the snow gets too deep.
大家要穿够衣服！
Everyone, wrap yourselves up
as fast as you can.
我们不应该走
We shouldn't go.
为什么？人人都走
Why not, Sam? Everyone's leaving.
我爸叫我躲在室内
When l talked to my dad,
he told me to stay inside.
出去遇上风雪一定死
The storm will kill anybody in it.
-你应该告诉他们
-对
-Then you have to say something.
-l know.
先生，你错了
Excuse me, sir, you're making a mistake.
我明白大家都怕
但我们已没有选择的余地
What? Listen, we're all scared,
but we've got no choice.
-我不是因为害怕
-准备出发吧
-That's not it.
-Get ready to go.
出去会冻死！
lf these people go outside,
they will freeze to death!
不要胡说八道
Okay, what is this nonsense?
不是胡说八道
风雪愈来愈猛
lt's not nonsense. All right?
Look, this storm is gonna get worse.
遇上会即冻死
The people caught outside
will freeze to death.
-你怎知道？
-我爸是气象专家
-Where are you getting this?
-My dad's a climatologist.
-他为政府工作
-那么我们应该怎样做？
-He works for the government.
-So what do we do?
躲在室内取暖，以不变应万变
We stay inside, we keep warm,
and we wait it out.
雪愈下愈深
The snow is getting deeper
by the minute.
我们会被困在这里
没有鲁食，补给K
We'd be trapped here
without food, supplies....
-是要冒险的，没错
-没有必要冒这个险
-lt's a risk, yeah--
-An unnecessary risk.
是有需要的
No, no. lt's not.
多讲浪费时间，我们走
We've wasted enough time talking.
Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
-等一等！考虑一下吧！
-走吧K
-Look, look. Just look for a second.
-Come on, everybody--
考虑一下！风雪会愈来愈猛
This storm is gonna get bad.
lt's gonna get really, really bad.
你们焙不过去！
You're not gonna be able to survive it.
信我吧
Believe me.
请你不要走
Sir, please just stay. Just stay.
总之不要K
Just don't....
-她可以走
-直接去后面
-She's set to go.
-Come on, straight to the back, guys.
我们要通讯将会很困难
It'll be impossible to reach each other.
在墨西哥城的美国领事馆
留个口讯给我
Leave a message for me
at the embassy in Mexico City.
我会
Okay, l will.
我爱你
l love you.
我爱你，积
l love you, Jack.
告诉森，我很爱他
Tell Sam l love him so much.
愿主保佑你
God be with you.
-贺医生
-是
-Doctor Hall?
-Yeah.
还未联络到彼得的父母
We haven't been able
to reach Peter's parents.
-我迟点再试
-谢谢你
-l'm gonna try later, okay?
-Okay. Thank you.
我帮你
l got it.
你应该去搭巴士南下
You're supposed to be on a bus
heading south.
我照顾你照顾了廿年
你觉得会让你单独去吗？
l've been watching your back for 20 years.
You think l'd let you go alone?
我以为一直是我照顾你
And all these years l thought
l was watching your back.
钥匙呢？
Where are the keys?
在货车里
ln the truck.
你想去哪里？
Where do you think you're going?
你们两个都没有方向感
Neither one of you can navigate
worth a damn.
没有我带路
你们会驶了去克里夫兰
Without me, you'll end up in Cleveland.
我会向你通报风雪情况
l'll try to give you updates on
the storm as it heads your way.
祝你好运
Good luck, Jack.
这是美国与墨西哥边境新闻直播
Breaking news from
the U.S.-Mexico border.
半小时前，墨西哥封锁边境K
Just half an hour ago,
Mexican officials closed the border...
大量美国难民K
...in the light of so many U.S. refugees
who are fleeing south...
为逃避风雪K
...in the wake of the approaching storm.
打算进入墨西哥
These people came in anticipation
of crossing into Mexico.
不过食了闭门眉
Instead, they've been met
with closed gates.
从来只有墨西哥人偷渡来美国K
And now, in a dramatic reversal
of illegal immigration...
现在大批美国人涌入墨西哥
...thousands of people are crossing
the Rio Grande into Mexico.
场面一片混乱，大家慌不择路
The scene unfolding here behind me
is one of desperation and frustration.
弃车徒步，挽着行李K
People have abandoned their cars,
grabbed their belongings...
涉水强渡大河，非法闯入墨西哥
...and they are wading across the river
illegally into Mexico.
就在这里
Here it is.
这火炉可能弃置了一百年
This fireplace probably hasn't
been used in about 1 00 years.
好
All right.
-你做什么？
-不烧书还有什么可以烧？
-What are you doing?
-What did you think we would burn?
-不可以烧书！
-绝对不可以！
-You can't burn books.
-No, absolutely not.
难道你们想冻死？
You want to freeze to death?
我去搬多一些来
l'll go get some more.
我帮手
l'll help you.
我同他们一起去
l'm going with them.
有没有餐厅或饭堂之类的地方？
Okay, do you have a cafeteria
or a lunchroom?
只有职员休息室
里面有自动售卖机
Just an employees' lounge
with a few vending machines.
单靠零食不能支持下去
We're not gonna last long
on M&M's and potato chips.
垃圾桶呢？
What about the garbage cans?
垃圾桶总有食物
There's always something
to eat in the garbage.
尼采？我们不可以烧尼采的书
Friedrich Nietzsche?
We can't burn Nietzsche.
他是十九世纪最重要的思想家
He was the most important thinker
of the 1 9th century.
尼采是恋妹狂、大男人主义猪罗
Please. He was a chauvinist pig
in love with his sister.
他不是大男人主义猪罗
He was not a chauvinist pig.
但他是恋妹狂
But he was in love with his sister.
不好意思，两位
Excuse me? You guys?
这下面有一大批税务书可以烧
Yeah, there's a whole section on tax law
down here that we can burn.
经几小时扰c，汽车由美国K
After hours of uncertainty,
the traffic is now moving smoothly...
开始顺利进入墨西哥
...from the United States into Mexico.
因为总统答应把南美国债K
This is only possible because the president
was able to negotiate a deal...
完全一笔勾消
换取边境开放
...to forgive all Latin American debt
in exchange for opening the border.
成千上万美国家庭正在逃往K
Now, multitudes of American families
are feeling a rush of relief....
露丝？
Lucy?
接彼得的救伤车到了吗？
ls Peter's ambulance here?
不会到
No.
-为什么？
-都驶走了
-Why?
-They've all gone.
-什么？
-大家都很迷惑K
-What?
-ln the confusion...
我不知道发生什么事
他们恐慌起来，一蜂窝走掉K
...l don't know what happened.
People started to panic, and they left....
-天啊
-有一个警察驾着铲雪车
-God.
-There's a policeman with a snowplow.
-他正在外面等候
-天啊
-He's waiting outside.
-God.
彼得只能坐救伤车
Peter can't be moved in anything
but an ambulance.
我留了口讯叫民安队派车来
l called and left a message
for the county ambulance service.
好的
Okay.
你走吧，我在这里等
Okay, you should go,
and l'll stay and wait.
露丝，不可以
Lucy, no.
-不
-不要紧
-No.
-No, you should go.
趁有车走吧
He's not gonna wait forever.
不要紧
lt's okay.
对不起
l'm sorry.
-不要紧
-好吧
-lt's okay.
-All right.
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事，只是较早前割伤了脚
Yeah, l'm fine. l just--
l cut my leg the other day.
接收到广播吗？
Did you get a signal?
一点点
Yeah, for a minute.
怎样？
And?
暴风雪无远弗致
Man, this storm is everywhere.
全面袭击北半球
lt's hit the entire Northern Hemisphere.
欧洲埋在十五尺雪下K
Europe is buried under
1 5 feet of snow...
美国的情况也将会同样恶劣
...and they say it's gonna get
just as bad here.
你爸不会来得到
l mean, l don't think your dad's
gonna make it.
他会来的
No, he'll make it.
他会
He'll make it.
白宫向北部各州K
The White House has ordered
a national disaster alert...
发出了全国灾难警告
...for all Northern states.
暴风雪可以致命
Continued exposure to
the approaching storm is deadly.
留在室内，尽量取暖K
Remain indoors and take all measures to
stay warm, burning any fuel sources...
静候风雪过去，纽约州以南K
...until the storm is over. Roads are
impassable across New York State...
大部分地区，所有道路不通行K
...as far south as Pennsylvania....
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
似乎在费城北面
Looks like we're just north
of Philadelphia.
小心！
Look out!
你们没事吧？
You guys okay?
-没事
-Yeah.
-再一次，道路K
-对不起，波士
-Once again, roads across the....
-Sorry, boss.
取出雪鞋来
Unpack the snowshoes.
我们从这里徒步
We're walking from here.
太太，要上路了
Come on, ma'am.
Let's get up and get going.
我们只来到布鲁克林
或者应该掉头
We've only made it to Brooklyn.
Maybe we should just turn back.
城市给水掩，结了冰，回去无用
Why? Half the city's frozen under water.
There's nothing to go back to.
起程了
Time to get up and keep moving.
我们应该留在图书馆内
What we should've done
is stayed in the library.
起行吧
Okay, guys, let's get moving.
醒来
Wake up.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
保暖
lnsulating.
报纸最好，不过这也可以
Newspaper's best, but this'll do.
露宿街头几年，学懂了怎样保暖
You know, you spend some years on the
streets and you learn how to keep warm.
给你
Hey.
多谢
Thanks.
有喇！
l got one.
你最喜欢哪一次假期？
Your favorite vacation.
除了这一次？
Besides this one?
好
All right.
几年前我陪爸去格钞兰做研究K
l went to Greenland with my dad on one
of his research trips a few years ago...
船坏了，进退不得
...and the ship broke down,
and we got stuck.
而且一直下着雨
And it rained constantly.
似乎沉闷得很
That sounds really boring.
其实好开心
But actually really nice, you know?
只有我们两父子，相处了十日
Just me and my dad
hanging out for 1 0 days.
（购物商场）
法兰！
Frank!
你怎样？
Are you all right?
我没事
l'm fine.
只是顺便落去购物
l just dropped in to do a little shopping.
我要割断雪橇
l gotta lose this sled.
等一等！我们会拉你上来
Hold on! We'll pull you up.
泽逊！你要撑着法兰的体重
Jason! You've got to support
Frank's weight.
得，我会尽力
Okay, l'll try.
我撑住了
Okay, l think l have his weight now.
我去你那里
l'm coming to you.
玻璃开始破裂！
The glass is breaking!
太重了
Too much weight.
支撑不住了
lt's not gonna hold.
不要割！不要割！
No. No.
法兰，我会救你出来
Frank. l can get you out.
不要割！
Don't do it!
-法兰，不要！
-No, Frank, no!
-Frank, no!
法兰！
Frank!
这是什么书？
What have you got there?
古本圣经
A Gutenberg Bible.
从珍贵藏书房那里拿来
lt was in the rare books room.
你以为神会救你？
You think God's gonna save you?
我不信神
No. l don't believe in God.
但你揽圣经揽得相当实
You're holding onto that Bible
pretty tight.
我要保护圣经
l'm protecting it.
这本圣经是第一本印刷的书籍
This Bible is the first book ever printed.
标志着理性时代的开始
lt represents the dawn
of the age of reason.
人类最重大的成就是文字
As far as l'm concerned, the written word
is mankind's greatest achievement.
要笑即管笑
You can laugh.
不过，假若西方文明完蛋K
But if Western civilization is finished...
我起码挽救了一小片
...l'm gonna save
at least one little piece of it.
我们听说有人未走
We heard somebody was left behind.
-我们驶来一部救伤车
-谢天谢地
-We brought an ambulance.
-Thank God.
非常多谢你来
Thank you so much for coming.
喂
Hey.
你没事吧？
Hey, are you all right?
你似乎发烧
You look like you have a fever
or something.
我没事，只是失眠
l'm fine. l just can't sleep.
不断想着无聊的问答比赛
My mind keeps going over
all those worthless decathlon facts.
-很无聊，是不是？
-并不是
-lt's pretty stupid, huh?
-No, it's all right.
你只是一时适应不来
l guess you just haven't had time
to adjust yet.
森，你叫我怎样可以适应？
How am l supposed to adjust, Sam?
我发愤读书，为了将来K
Everything l've ever cared about,
everything l've worked for...
怎知道没有将来
...has all been preparation
for a future that no longer exists.
我知道你一直觉得
我太认真对待问答游戏
l know you always thought l took
the competition too seriously.
你说得对
You were right.
-一切都是枉费心机
-不，不，我K
-lt was all for nothing.
-No, no. l--
其实我只是回避真正原因
No, l just-- l just said that
to avoid admitting the truth.
关于什么？
Truth about what?
关于我参加问答比赛的原因
About why l joined the team.
我参赛是为了你
l joined it because of you.
喂
Hey.
我知道
l know.
-总统先生
-好
-Mr. President.
-All right.
对不起，我们不能再等
l'm sorry, sir, we can't wait any longer.
只走剩我们最后一批
We're the last ones.
好
All right.
控制中心
Mexicali Control, this is Delta 26.
（墨西哥，美国难民营）
有紧急讯息
We've got an urgent message
for high command.
要求优先降落
Request priority for landing zone one.
收到，会有交通工具在地面等待
Roger that, Delta 26.
Transport will be waiting.
-长官
-谢谢，下士
-Sir.
-Thank you, corporal.
-长官，对不起来迟了
-去吧
-Sorry for the delay, sir.
-Carry on.
国务肱士
Madam Secretary.
副总统
Raymond.
总统队伍遇上暴风雪
The president's motorcade
got caught in the storm.
无一生还
They didn't make it.
她今朝早没醒来K
And she wouldn't wake up
this morning. l--
她昨晚只是发烧
She only had a fever.
l don't understand.
她的面色十分苍白
She's awfully pale.
我们已经几日没食过东西
None of us has had anything
real to eat in days.
-是体温过低
-怎会是体温过低？
-lt's hypothermia.
-But how can it be hypothermia?
-我们都在这里K
-或者只是感冒
-We've all been in--
-Maybe it's the flu.
不是感冒
No, no, it's not the flu.
你怎么知道呢？
And how do you know?
书不只是可以用来烧
她有什么病征？
Books can be good for things other
than burning. What are her symptoms?
她发烧，而且标冷汗
l told you that she has a fever and her--
She's got a really cold sweat.
脉搏呢？
How's her pulse?
-跳得很快
-她有没有受伤？
-lt's really fast.
-Does she have any injuries?
例如一些可能受到感染的伤口？
Like a cut that might have
gotten infected?
几日前她好像割伤了脚
She was complaining about a cut
on her leg a few days ago.
我当时不怎样为意
l didn't think anything of it.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
是血液中毒，败血病
That's blood poisoning. Septicemia.
可能会发生w毒休克
She could go into septic shock.
我见过，可以很严重
l've seen that before.
That can get bad.
急需大量盘尼西林K
She needs a massive dose
of penicillin...
或广效抗生素，否则K
...or a broad-spectrum
antibiotic immediately, or....
否则怎样？
Or what?
我从未见过这现象
l've never seen anything like it.
只见到云，什么都见不到
There's no point of reference.
All l can see is cloud cover.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
拍摄热流的红外线照片
Taking infrared image of thermal currents.
然后传去侯斯顿，也传去
你们俄罗斯的气候观察站
Send to Houston, Korolev,
your weather service.
我帮你手
l'll help you.
汤？汤，醒来
Tom? Tom, wake up.
太空站传来卫星照片
你最好看一看
l just received some satellite images from
the space station. You better take a look.
这个东西有几大？
How big is this thing?
x歹直径有五十里
The vortex is 50 miles in diameter.
还在增大
欧洲、亚洲的两个单体风暴更大
And growing. The two cells
over Europe and Asia are even bigger.
惨
Good God.
这一个会在一小时内袭击纽约
This one's gonna hit New York
inside an hour.
泽逊？
Jason!
你怎样？
Are you all right?
泽逊！
Jason!
-你做什么？
-那只船上必定有药物
-What are you doing?
-There's gotta be medicine on that ship.
你说过出去好危险
l thought you said it was too dangerous
to go outside.
对，我说过
l know l did.
你在哪里找到椅子？
Where did you find those chairs?
为什么？
Why?
我同你一起去
l'm going with you.
我也去
Me too.
开门呀，岂有此理！
Come on, damn it!
-统统是俄文
-我知道
-lt's all in Russian. l--
-l know.
-找到了
-什么？你怎么知道？
-Hey, hey, hey, guys. l found it.
-What? How do you know?
因为娟上写着“盘尼西林”
Because it says ''penicillin''
on the bottle.
等一等，这是饭堂
Hey, wait. This is the mess hall.
-应该有鲁食
-我们没有时间找鲁食
-We should find some food.
-We don't have time.
缺鲁的话，连罗拉也会饿死
Listen, none of us are gonna survive much
longer without food. lncluding Laura.
好吧
Okay.
-这里！
-什么？
-Sam, over here.
-What?
找到了
Bingo.
拜仁
Brian?
-我没受伤
-什么事？
-l'm okay.
-What happened?
我只是打开柜门
All l did was open up the cupboard.
-我可以用得着
-用来运载鲁食
-Well, we can use it.
-Put food in it.
拉他进去！
Pull him in, Brian!
-你怎样？
-惨了，不只一只
-You all right?
-Oh, my God, there's more.
我只脚伤了
My leg.
用这条包扎
Here, use this.
它应该已经到达纽约上空
lt should be over New York by now.
卫星探测的资料显示
气温每秒下降十度
Satellite readings are showing a temperature
drop of 1 0 degrees per second.
各位K
You guys...
我相信我们在风眼里
...l think we're in the eye of it.
要赶快回去
We gotta get back right now.
我会出去把狼引走
Look, l'm gonna go outside, and l'm gonna
lure the wolves out of the room.
狼一走，你把门锁上
When they leave, you lock the door.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-拜仁，快点
-我要一些工具
-Brian, hurry.
-l need something.
快点！
Come on, hurry!
拜仁！拜仁，开门！
Brian! Brian, open the door!
我们要走了
We have to get out of here now.
拜仁，搬补给品
Brian, get the supplies.
我们走
Oh, shit. Let's go!
拉！
Pull, Brian!
把药物拿去给罗拉
Take the medicine to Laura.
我们快到了，来吧！
We're almost there. Come on!
拜仁！关门！
Brian! Close the door!
不要让火熄灭！
Don't let the fire go out!
发生什么事？
What's happening?
阿宝，离开那道门！
Buddha, come away from the door.
来，阿宝！
Come, Buddha, come!
烧多些书！烧多些书！
More books! More books!
我昏迷了几耐？
How long have l been out of it?
几个钟头
Couple hours.
觉得怎样？
How do you feel?
还好，发生什么事？
Okay. What happened?
我一时情急，把你推进来
Well, we had to get inside in kind of
a hurry, so l sort of pushed you in.
我习惯被你推推赶赶
l should be used to you
pushing me around.
你醒来真好
Good to have you back.
你做什么？
What are you doing?
风眼已经过去
而我们离曼哈顿四十里
The eye of the storm has passed,
and we're 40 miles from Manhattan.
不等多一日？
Shouldn't we wait one more day?
森未必可以再焙多一日
Sam may not have one more day.
（史提顿岛区）
我们会怎样？
What do you think's
gonna happen to us?
你指什么？
What do you mean?
我指我们、文明世界、人类
l mean us. Civilization. Everybody.
人类既然焙过了上一个冰河时期K
Mankind survived the last lce Age.
也有能力焙过这一个
We're certainly capable
of surviving this one.
全视乎我们能不能借着这次教训
去V取经验
All depends on whether or not
we're able to learn from our mistakes.
我希望我还有机会
可以用到这次教训所V取的经验
l sure as hell would like a chance
to learn from mine.
你已经尽了力
You did everything you could.
我指的是阿森
l was thinking about Sam.
你知道阿森的生存机会K
Jack, you know the chances of Sam....
我对我的儿子作出了一个承诺
l made my son a promise.
我决定守诺言
l'm going to keep it.
柏加，这是侯斯顿，听到吗？
Parker, this is Houston. Do you read?
收到，请讲
Roger, mission control. Go ahead.
我们接到报告，北美的暴风雪正在消散
We've got scattered reports that
the storm is dissipating over North America.
你可不可以确定？
Can you confirm?
正确，终于消散了
Affirmative. lt's finally clearing.
我们在欧洲上空
We're over Europe right now.
几日来第一次见到陆地
l can see landmass
for the first time in days.
我们离图书馆有几远？
How much further is it to the library?
它应该K
lt should be...
在这里
...right here.
我很替你难过，积
l'm sorry, Jack.
森？
Sam?
那人是谁？
Who is that?
我爸爸
My father.
你来到了
You made it.
当然
Of course l did.
（美国领事馆）
EMBASSY OF THE UNlTED STATES
OF AMERlCA
总统先生
Mr. President.
刚刚接到贺积的消息
l've just received a shortwave
radio transmission from Jack Hall.
他抵达了纽约
He made it to New York.
那里还有生还者
He says there are survivors.
多谢你，汤
Thank you, Tom.
那是K
That's....
好消息
That's good news.
过去数周，面对大自然摧毁力K
These past few weeks have left us all
with a profound sense of humility...
不得不深切感受到人力的渺小
...in the face of nature's
destructive power.
多年来，我们以为可以K
For years, we operated under the belief
that we could continue...
任意损耗地球资源
而无须付出代价
...consuming our planet's natural resources
without consequence.
我们错了
We were wrong.
我错了
I was wrong.
现在，我在国外首次全国广播K
The fact that my first address to you
comes from a consulate on foreign soil...
此举见证了我们处境的巨变
...is a testament to our changed reality.
不仅美国人K
Not only Americans...
全世界的人现在都在K
...but people all around the globe
are now guests in the nations...
我们称为第三世界的地方作客
...we once called The Third World.
危难中，得到他们收容
In our time of need,
they have taken us in and sheltered us.
雪中送炭，我感激不已
And I am deeply grateful
for their hospitality.
我们为有勇气作出疏散指示的已故总统
致以深切的哀悼K
We mourn the loss of a spirited leader
whose courageous order to evacuate....
彼得？你觉得怎样？
Peter? Hey, you feeling okay today?
这几日来，我为困在北方的人K
For days, we've despaired
about the fate of the people...
忧心瘦瘦
...who are trapped in the North.
今日，露出了希望
Today, there is cause for hope.
几小时前，消息传来K
Only a few hours ago, I received word
that a small group of people...
在纽约市，一小群人K
...survived in New York City
against all odds...
挺过严m气候，绝处逢生
...and in the face
of tremendous adversity.
我下令救援队立即载他们回来K
I've ordered an immediate
search-and-rescue mission...
并且搜索生还者
...to bring them home
and to look for more survivors.
积！
Jack!
见到你真好，上机吧
lt's good to see you.
Come on, let's go get on board.
看
Look at that.
什么？
What?
有没有见过那样清淅的天空？
Have you ever seen the air so clear?